orgjunkie.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - I'm an Organizing Junkie

I’m an Organizing Junkie found at https://orgjunkie.com (“Website”) is governed by this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) as outlined below.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

 **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** :

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment or subscribing to my newsletter.

 **Information We Collect from Others** :

We may receive information about you from other sources.  For example, you may link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile.  If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile, we will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

 **Automatically-Collected Information** :

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

 **Comments:**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment. If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

 **Media:**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

 **Embedded content from other sites:**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **Cookies and Web Beacons** :

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit orgjunkie.com. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of my features, such as Org Junkie’s Printables Library.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies are retained indefinitely.

AdThrive:

I also use third party advertisements to support orgjunkie.com. This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents:

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **More about cookies:**

-Cookies are small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience.

-The cookies cannot identify you.

-In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences and provide anonymized tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.

-As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better.

-However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others.

-The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.

-I suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

-To opt out of Google Analytics cookies, [visit this page at tools.google.com](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). [This page describes how Google uses cookie data](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/) from this site.

## How your information may be used:

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

-To operate and maintain the Website.

-To send you promotional information, such as newsletters, blog post updates, and special offers. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings.

-To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts.

-To respond to your comments or inquiries.

-To provide you with user support.

-To track and measure advertising on the Website.

-To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

## Who we share your data with

Service Providers and others who help with our business operations and assist in the delivery of our products and services including, but not limited to, application development, site hosting, maintenance, data analysis, infrastructure provision, IT services, customer service, email delivery services, payment processing, marketing, analytics.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

 **Google Analytics:  **

We use Google Analytics to record information about the pages a user has seen, for example the URL of the page, time of day, device used, etc. The information that we collect is anonymized and sent to Google Analytics for analysis. Google Analytics mainly uses first-party cookies to report on visitor interactions on this website. Users may disable cookies or delete any individual cookie. [Learn more](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies)

In addition, Google Analytics supports an optional browser [add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) that – once installed and enabled – disables measurement by Google Analytics for any site a user visits. Note that this add-on only disables Google Analytics measurement.

Google Analytics also collects Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to provide and protect the security of the service, and to give website owners a sense of which country, state, or city in the world their users come from (also known as “IP geolocation”).

See [this page for Google Analytics security and usage of data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). Google Analytics data is retained for 38 months.

 **Mad Mimi:**

This service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your email address for purposes of delivering such communications. I am the only person who has access to it. Please refer to the [Mad Mimi/GoDaddy Privacy Policy ](https://www.godaddy.com/Agreements/Privacy.aspx)for further information. If you would like your view and click information to NOT be tracked, please email me at organizingjunkie@gmail.com with your request. If you would like to take care of this yourself, click the PREFERENCES button at the bottom of any of my emails.

This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

At times, our newsletter may be used for advertising purposes. Newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

## Anonymous data

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

## Publicly visible information

If you leave a comment on the Website, certain information may be publicly visible.  Your email address will never be available publicly.  At your option, you may also add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website. You may also choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and Google Account. Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

## Retargeting ads:

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

## Affiliate program participation:

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

 **Amazon:**

I’m an Organizing Junkie is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

## Rights related to your personal information:

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify me at organizingjunkie@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information I have about you by submitting a request to organizingjunkie@gmail.com.

Amend – You may contact me at organizingjunkie@gmail.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that I erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to organizingjunkie@gmail.com.

Most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of Interest Based Advertising. If you would like to find out more information, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

Please note that I may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

## Where we send your data

Third parties have access to your data as noted within this agreement.

## Protection of personal data

We use reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect personal data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the nature of the Personal Data and risks involved in processing that information.

## Sensitive personal information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Children’s information

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13 in its database, please contact us immediately at organizingjunkie@gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records. By using the Services, you are representing to us that you are not under the age of 13.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Website may change this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes are effective immediately upon posting. Please review this Privacy Policy frequently to stay updated on changes that may affect you. Your continued use of this website signifies your continuing consent to be bound by this Privacy Policy.

## Contact information

At any time, please contact me at organizingjunkie@gmail.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

 _This policy goes into effect on May 25, 2018._
